Suryaprakash Pal

Certified Linux & Network support Engineer with 3 years experience.

Indore, Madhya Pradesh suryaprakashpal9_t3e@indeedemail.com 8889115933

An Enthusiastic and Diligent professional, a Red hat and Cisco Certified Engineer working on creating, managing and Developing LINUX servers and Network. Have total 6 years of experience in Technical and Non technical fields.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Linux Support Engineer.

DAVV University Indore

March 2019 to Present

- Configuration and Management of Web servers Apache (http, https) DHCP
- server, DNS server. •
- Configuration and Management of LVM.
- Installation and configuration of LAMP on Centos Remote administration of Linux server using ssh, vnc viewer
- Managing different file Servers like, NFS, FTP and SAMABA servers.
- Responsible for adding, creating, new users, groups and setup home directories and appropriate access restrictions to software and directories & file using access modes.
- Configuration of FTP and remote application like ssh, scp , telnet.
- Responsible for installation, configuration, management and maintenance over linux systems.
- Installation, configuration and Management of Xen server with Cirtix
- Application (Learning)
- Installation and Management of KVM Virtual machine. •
- Taking Backup on Daily basis via RSync and Tar in incremental Basis
- Backup and Restoration files.
- Installation and Managing of Ansible and Ansible Playbook files to Create
- Automation environment. •
- Installing software in Linux.
- Desgin LAN & configure switch with VLANS.
- Upgrading and Updating Servers on Daily Basis. •
- Configuration and Management of Mysql server••
- Configuration and Management of HP Aruba
- switches2530 Digisol D-link, (L2 & L3) 2530.•

IT Support

Nesit Ltd

December 2018 to March 2019

- Troubleshoot and manage network problems
- Check PC configuration for online exams.

- Audit different colleges for online exams suitability.
- Create and manage separate LAN network for online exams.

Network Engineer

Orlando Academy & Solution C-DAC ACTS & Walrus Solution Pvt Ltd October 2017 to October 2018

Creating LINUX server for conducting the professional exam worked as a server administrator.

- Handled bio metric entry, documentation and candidate crowd who came to give exam.
- Check for client PC configurations.
- Provide Training to the team for developing the server.
- Troubleshooting network related issues such as Wi-Fi and LAN connectivity
- Inventory computer, Network equipment and accessories.
- Network connectivity troubleshooting, ping, tracert, telnet.
- Configuring and troubleshooting Desktops and Laptops hardware related problems.
- Handled command center for online exam
- Attending the call of Invigilators and resolving their server related problem.

Hardware and Networking Engineer

Laxyo Energy Ltd

August 2016 to August 2017

- Assembling & dissembling of computers.
- Installing, maintaining & troubleshooting different operating Systems.
- Installation, Configuration of Network Printer & Local Printers.
- Configuring and troubleshooting of mail clients (MS Outlook).
- Backup and Restore System Data.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of operating Systems(Win8, Win8.1, Win 10, Redhat, Centos 7, Ubuntu, Mint)

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in ELECTRONIC & INSTRUMENTATION

RGPV Bhopal (M.P)

June 2008 to June 2012

Higher Secondary(12th Pass) in Scinece

RRMB Gujarati - Indore, Madhya Pradesh June 2006 to June 2007

Secondary(10th Pass)

ST GEORAGE HIGH SCHOOL Indore - Indore, Madhya Pradesh June 2004 to June 2005

Skills / IT Skills

- Routing
- Switching
- Ansible
- Webserver
- Ftp
- DNS
- DHCP
- Vlan
- KVM
- Samba
- CCNA
- Xen server
- Switching
- Vlan
- Operations Management
- User Management
- NFS

Certifications and Licenses

RHCSA

CCNA R&S

CCNA security

NSE 1 Network Security Associate

NSE 2 network Security Associate

ICSI Network Security Specialist